{
	"1":{
		"Question": "George Washington Gale was an American civil engineer. He is credited to have created the centerpiece of the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago. What was Gale’s eponymous creation, which is a landmark feature in cities such as Singapore, LasVegas, London,Vienna, among others?",

		"Answer": "Ferris Wheel"
	},

	"2":{
		"Question": "Flygskam is the most popular among a group of similar meaning European words to have become prominent in 2019, thanks to the rising fame of a person. The person avoided Flygskam by travelling from England to the US on the Malizia II and back to Spain on the La Vagabonde.",

		"Answer": "Greta Thunberg. Flygskam - The feeling of shame from flying in an airplane, knowing how much carbon pollution it causes"
	},

	"3":{
		"Question": "After a long and arduous search, the artists went with the original novel cover as the inspiration. However, they added one element to add perspective since people were not able to gauge the size of the creature (which was misinterpreted as baby-size to King Kong by the test audience). Which iconic movie? What was the additional element that they added to the original book cover? ",

		"Answer": "Jurassic Park The backdrop of the forest and the small trees"
	},

	"4":{
		"Question": "Which two changes in which activities? During the Middle Ages, the rise of the Christian clergy and strong female monarchs in Europe led to a signiﬁcant loss of inﬂuence of the position of the Prime Minister or the Grand Minister, which was usually the second-in-command in most Islamic courts of Europe and Asia Minor. Two enduring consequences of this are in two recreational activities based on royal courts, which had come to Europe thanks to Islamic traders and invaders. These changes have become the universally accepted standards today in the two activities.",

		"Answer": "Playing Cards and Chess. In Playing Cards, the Queen was promoted in rank, and the prime minister was rebranded as the jester or Jack and demoted. In Chess, the Wazir/Minister was rebranded as Queen. The Oont/Camel, which was the Minister’s ride, was rebranded as the Bishop."
	},

	"5":{
		"Question": "According to Harsh Mariwala, one key reason for X’s success was the packaging used. In the 70s, Y was sold in tins. They wanted to move to plastic as it was cheaper than tins and plastic bottles would look more attractive on the shelves. Traders however were reluctant as rats feasted on the bottles and Y oozed out, spoiling other products kept near them. This led to the product team deciding to use superior plastic in round leak proof bottle, which now everyone associates with the brand. Which company?",

		"Answer": "Parachute"
	},

	"6":{
		"Question": "Two guys in California with a state of the art windtunnel set to find out whether something which most cyclists do makes them faster or not. They tested a number of riders across the entire spectrum of what they called the Chewbacca scale. They tested him with ____, and then they tested him without ____. They found that he was significantly faster the second time around. So what is it that cyclists do, originally done to recover more quickly from road rash after crashes, and so that it hurt less during a massage?",

		"Answer": "Why cyclists shave their legs"
	},

	"7":{
		"Question": "In 1960s Chicago, retail store managers started wearing a soft whistle, which they blew every time they saw customers of a particular kind. The whistle would indicate to other employees to ﬂock over to the customer, sweet talk them, and attend them at all times till they check-out. This simple method did wonders for the store bottom-line, often posting 15-20% better results. As one manager said, 'what a person wears, how they walks, how they talks, tells lots about what kind they is. And you'd be surprised, it ain't a color thing neither.'",

		"Answer": "Potential Shoplifters"
	},

	"8":{
		"Question": "The quote occurs in the anime’s 2nd season, when the characters are discussing the proper method to have a tea party and a suggestion is made to tie the hair backwards in a ponytail-like knot in the classical style of Nobunaga, in order to properly have a tea-drinking ceremony. What remark - made about the way to prepare tea and tie hair - am I on about?",

		"Answer": "Ah! I see you are a man of culture as well!"
	},

	"9":{
		"Question": "Ancient Romans had their own unique ways of executing criminals. They were not just hanged or beheaded. Rather, their death was also put to a use, to make something seem more realistic. • How were such death sentences carried out?",

		"Answer": "The criminals were used as actors in plays for the death scenes. So, when a character was to be killed in a scene, a real criminal was killed and a real killing took place on the stage which also made the play look more realistic."
	},

	"10":{
		"Question": "In the year 1963, The State Mutual Life Assurance Company of Worcester, Massachusetts (now known as Hanover Insurance) had purchased Guarantee Mutual Company of Ohio. The merger resulted in low employee morale. In an attempt to solve this, a graphic designer named Harvey Ross Ball was employed as a freelance artist by the company, to come up with an image to increase the employee morale. In less than ten minutes, Harvey Ross Ball came up with a simple yet world-changing image. He was paid $45 for his iconic creation by the executives of The State Mutual Life Assurance Company. The use of this image became part of the company's friendship campaign whereby State Mutual handed out hundreds of buttons with this image printed upon to it’s employees. What famous image did Harvey Ross Ball create?",

		"Answer": "Smiley Face :)"
	},

	"11":{
		"Question": "_Erythema ab igne_ also known as the “toasted skin syndrome” is a skin condition caused by long-term exposure to heat. Patients complain of mild itchiness and a burning sensation, but often, unless a change in pigmentation is seen, it can go unnoticed. What has been reported as one of the top causes for the same, a consequence of our tech saviness?",

		"Answer": "Resting laptop on thighs"
	},

	"12":{
		"Question": "Apocryphally, this company was started when its co-founder was fined $40 for failing to return a product he had rented from what would become his companies future rival. He and his partner then tested sending out their product via the US postal mail service, and upon discovering that it reached intact, they started the company in 1997. As technology improved, the company moved into becoming the fully online behemoth it is today. Which company?",

		"Answer": "Netflix"
	},

	"13":{
		"Question": "A trip to space is certainly be a life-changing one. For Scott Kelly, it quite literally was. NASA sent Scott to the International Space Station for a one-year mission to study the effects of space on the human body, while his twin brother Mark kept his feet firmly planted on Earth. When Scott returned back to Earth, scientists discovered a fundamental change between Scott and his twin, Mark, and the research made news all around the world. What was this change, that was brought about by the conditions of space?",

		"Answer": "There was a significant change in his DNA between him and his twin brother"
	},

	"14":{
		"Question": "X is a popular powdered flavouring introduced by Thomas Mayne during the Great Depression, to help children get enough nutrients in their diet. The name X is borrowed from an athlete of Greek Mythology. A person known for his remarkable strength, capable of carrying heavy weights, the name X seemed to be a perfect fit for the namesake product, given its apparent effect on its consumer. Initially sold in several outlets in Australia, the drink was popularized in several countries through various distribution channels. Give X, which forms a cherished part of our childhood.",

		"Answer": "Milo"
	},

	"15":{
		"Question": "One of the darkest chapters in modern history took place between November and December 1979 when extremist insurgents calling for the overthrow of the House of Saud took over the Masjid-al-Haram in Mecca, Saudi Arabia. The seizure of Islam's holiest site, the taking of hostages from among the worshipers, and the deaths of hundreds of militants, security forces and hostages caught in crossfire in the ensuing battles for control of the site, all shocked the Islamic world. Being one of the holiest sites of Islam, it is forbidden for blood to be spilt at the mosque, and the Pakistani Army, who were supporting the Saudis in regaining control of the mosque, suggested an alternative method to terminate the terrorists harboured in the mosque without blood spill and gunfire. Though ultimately rejected, what was the method proposed by the Pakistani Army?",

		"Answer": "The Pakistanis proposed to flood the mosque and then pass high voltage current through the water, thereby electrocuting the insurgents without having to fire shots at them."
	},

	"16":{
		"Question": "The Anti X Party is a Swiss political party dedicated to decreasing professional use of X, which the party claims 'causes national- economic damage amounting to 2.1 billion CHF' and lowers the quality of business in '95% of the cases'. The party advocates flip charts as an alternative to X. What are we talking about/what does the party want to restrict?",

		"Answer": "Microsoft Powerpoint"
	}

}